A habit he would keep for the rest of his life.
Of his well -off parents, he came to inherit so much money that he would never have to work.
Instead, he devoted his time to thinking, often lying in his bed.
After completing his education, he broke with the higher social life in Paris
And moved to Amsterdam where he came to stay for most of his life.
Descartes came to criticize philosophy for unable to provide reliable knowledge.
Various philosophical theories collided with each other,
And there was no way to determine what was true and what was false.
The reason for this, Descartes said, was that philosophy lacked a safe foundation
- An undoubtedly confident truth to be based on.
This is unlike, for example, mathematics.
The reason we can construct complex mathematical theories is because we agree on how
Mathematics works at its most basic level - for example 1+1 = 2
Or that a straight line is the shortest stretch between two points.
Something equivalent does not exist in philosophy, which is why we can never say anything with certainty.
Could it now, asked Descartes, be possible to find something equivalent in philosophy?
If one could find batches outside the mathematics whose truths were impossible to doubt
These could be used as a starting point for logical conclusions in philosophy.
In his search for a secure basis for philosophical knowledge, he used a method called systematic doubt.
He himself tried to doubt everything, in order to in this way hope to find something that could not be questioned
- Something that must be undoubtedly true.
He soon realized that experiences based on our senses (eg vision, hearing, feeling)
were not sufficiently safe to constitute undoubted knowledge.
This is because we always risk perceiving something wrong.
In fact, we can't even be sure if we are awake or dreaming, Descartes said.
Our senses are sufficient to navigate in everyday life,
But not to form the basis for absolute and undoubted truth.
Remains then do our reason, our thinking, but this too can doubt Descartes.
What if there is an evil demon that lurks us every time we count math
- Thus, even mathematics is undoubtedly true.
But if now neither our senses nor our reason can give us secure truth,
Is there something that cannot be doubted?
There is, says Descartes.
The only thing we can be absolutely sure of is that we have the experiences we have.
Although you can doubt that there is an outer world, you cannot doubt that you have the experience of it.
This is true even if you look wrong, dream or be fooled.
From this we can draw certain conclusions.
This means that we are some kind of existing being.
You do not necessarily know your own nature, but that you exist stands beyond doubt.
Because even if you are deceived by an evil demon, someone is cheated.
In addition, we know with absolute certainty that one is a creature
Which, if nothing else, has at least conscious experiences.
Descartes summarized this conclusion in a famous Latin phrase: "Cogito Ergo sum",
Which is translated to "I think, so I am".
This is the foundation of knowledge.
Then Descartes began to rebuild the world.
He began by trying to prove God's existence with a variant of the classical ontological proof of God:
1. God is by definition the greatest imaginable.
2. Suppose God does not exist.
4. In this case, this is greater than God, as it is greater to exist than not to exist.
5. However, this leads to a paradox, since God by definition is the greatest imaginable.
6. The assumption that God does not exist is thus incorrect.
When Descartes assured himself of the existence of God, he also meant that everything we perceive with our minds
Must be true when God would not allow us to be fooled.
The reason why, after all, we sometimes wrong depends on our free will, which exceptionally leads us to incorrect reviews.
God also guarantees that our reason is not fooled by any external influence,
Why the world is as it appears to us.
The most important thing about Descarte's philosophy is his method.
He methodically reasoning and avoids speculation
(at least until he mixes God into the reasoning),
And thus lays the foundation for how modern philosophy is conducted.
Unlike an empiricist who believes that knowledge has its basis in experiences.
Like many other rationalists, Descartes, in addition to philosopher, was also mathematicians.
He saw insights into mathematics as fundamental to understanding the world
- A thought he shared with, for example, Pythagoras and Plato.
One morning, Descartes, his habit was faithful, and meditated
When he saw a fly flew around the room.
He realized that one could describe the position of the fly by indicating its distance
to three walls with a common corner.
Each position at a point in the room or plane could be described with speech called coordinates,
and a point in motion could be described with equations.
He had just invented the coordinate system.
Descartes also improved the algebraic notation by introducing exponents
and the Convention to designate unknown quantities with letters from the end of the alphabet
and known quantities with letters from the beginning of the alphabet.
Even before this, letters had been started to denote quantities,
But a notation was used that was quite cumbersome.
The equation that with Descartes notation would be written like this:
were previously written as:
Even what we today feel as Newton's first team, or the inertia, was first formulated by Descartes.
Thus, he is also one of the forerunners in modern physics.
One of those who admired Descartes was Queen Kristina of Sweden,
And she invited the philosopher to Stockholm to give her private lessons in philosophy.
He reluctantly accepted but came to suffer severely from the cold winter.
He himself must have described Sweden as a bears' land between cliffs and ice
Where even people's thoughts freeze to ice.
In addition, Descartes, who never ever got up before 11 am, was ordered to keep their lessons at 5 in the morning.
Within two weeks he suffered pneumonia and died shortly thereafter at Stockholm Castle.
Here we have Sweden's biggest contribution to philosophy history
- Our climate killed one of world history's greatest thinkers.
As a deeply believing Catholic in Protestant Sweden, it was unthinkable to bury him in weighted soil.
Instead, he was buried at a cemetery for undone children, but this posed new problems.
To accommodate the philosopher in a coffin adapted for children, it was decided to cut off his head.
As if this were not bad enough, the head was also lost.
This was first discovered 16 years later when France after diplomatic pressure
Got the coffin excavated and shipped to Paris for a statesman's funeral.
It was not until 150 years later that Descartes Kranium was found by the father of Swedish chemistry, Jacob Berzelius,
And it could be returned to Paris.
How the French reacted when they discovered that the Swedes have fun to
Carve out scribbles and neglect the lower jaw do not tell the story.
For some unfathomable reason, this time it was also possible to reunite the body parts.
Instead placed the skull on a shelf in the science museum in Paris
Where there is still the view- squeezed between a pair of Neanderthal and Cromagnon shells.